Hi, my name is Frank,
مرحبا، اسمي فرانك،
and I collect secrets.
وأنا أجمع الأسرار.
It all started with a crazy idea
بدأ كل شيء بفكرة جنونية
in November of 2004.
في نوفمبر 2004.
I printed up 3,000 self-addressed postcards,
طبعت ما يصل إلى 3000 بطاقة بريدية ذاتية العنونة،
just like this.
تماما مثل هذه.
They were blank on one side,
كانت فارغة من جهة،
and on the other side
وعلى الجهة الأخرى
I listed some simple instructions.
وضعت بعض التعليمات البسيطة.
I asked people to anonymously share an artful secret
طلبت من الناس وبشكل مجهول أن يشاركوا سرا ماكرا
they'd never told anyone before.
لم يخبروه أحدا من قبل.
And I handed out these postcards randomly
وقد وزعت هذه البطاقات البريدية بعشوائية
on the streets of Washington, D.C.,
على شوارع واشنطن العاصمة،
not knowing what to expect.
دون معرفة ما أتوقعه.
But soon the idea began spreading virally.
لكن الفكرة بدأت قريبا تنتشر بشكل فيروسي.
People began to buy their own postcards
بدأ الناس يشترون بطاقات بريدية خاصة بهم
and make their own postcards.
ويجعلونها بطاقات بريدية لهم.
I started receiving secrets in my home mailbox,
بدأت أتلقى الأسرار في صندوق بيتي في المنزل،
not just with postmarks from Washington, D.C.,
ليس فقط بختم بريدي من واشنطن العاصمة،
but from Texas, California,
بل من تكساس وكاليفورنيا،
Vancouver, New Zealand, Iraq.
وفانكوفر ونيوزيلاندا والعراق.
Soon my crazy idea didn't seem so crazy.
وسرعان ما لم تعد فكرتي الجنونية تبدو بتلك الجنونية.
PostSecret.com
PostSecret.com
is the most visited advertisement-free blog in the world.
هو أكثر المدونات الخالية من الإشهار زيارة في العالم.
And this is my postcard collection today.
وهذه مجموعتي من البطاقات البريدية اليوم.
You can see my wife
يمكنكم أن تروا زوجتي
struggling to stack a brick of postcards
تكافح من أجل تكويم لبنة من البطاقات البريدية
on a pyramid of over a half-million secrets.
على هرم من أكثر من نصف مليون سر.
What I'd like to do now
ما أود القيام به الآن
is share with you a very special handful of secrets
هو مشاركتكم حفنة من الأسرار المميزة
from that collection,
من تلك المجموعة،
starting with this one.
بدء بهذه.
"I found these stamps as a child,
"وجدت هذه الطوابع البريدية كطفل،
and I have been waiting all my life
وقد كنت أنتظر طوال حياتي
to have someone to send them to.
ليكون لدي شخص أرسلها له.
I never did have someone."
لم أكن أعي لمن سأرسلها."
Secrets can take many forms.
قد تتخذ الأسرار أشكالا عدة.
They can be shocking
قد تكون صادمة
or silly or soulful.
أو سخيفة أو عاطفية.
They can connect us to our deepest humanity
قد تربطنا بإنسانيتنا العميقة
or with people we'll never meet.
أو مع أشخاص لم نلتق بهم قط.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
Maybe one of you sent this one in.
ربما أحدكم قد أرسل لي هذه.
I don't know.
لا أعرف.
This one does a great job of demonstrating
هذه تقوم بعمل عظيم في عرض
the creativity that people have
إبداعية الناس
when they make and mail me a postcard.
حين ينشئون ويرسلون بطاقة بريدية.
This one obviously was made out of half a Starbucks cup
هذه قد تم تصميمها بوضوح باستعمال نصف كأس ستاربكس
with a stamp and my home address written on the other side.
مع طابع وعنواني الشخصي مكتوب على الجهة الأخرى.
"Dear Birthmother, I have great parents.
"إلى أمي التي ولدتني، لدي والدان عظيمان.
I've found love. I'm happy."
وقد وقعت في الحب. أنا سعيد."
Secrets can remind us of the countless human dramas,
قد تذكرنا الأسرار بكم لا يحصى من الدراما الإنسانية،
of frailty and heroism,
من الضعف والبطولة،
playing out silently
وهي تلعب بصمت
in the lives of people all around us
في حياة الناس من حولنا
even now.
حتى الآن.
"Everyone who knew me before 9/11
"كل من عرفني قبل 9/11
believes I'm dead."
يعتقد أنني ميت."
"I used to work with a bunch of uptight religious people,
"كنت أشتغل مع متشددين دينيا،
so sometimes I didn't wear panties,
لذا لا أرتدي سراويل داخلية أحيانا،
and just had a big smile and chuckled to myself."
وأبتسم فقط وأقهقه لنفسي."
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
This next one takes a little explanation before I share it with you.
السر التالي يحتاج بعض الشرح قبل أن أشارككم إياه.
I love to speak on college campuses
أحب أن أتحدث في الجامعات
and share secrets and the stories with students.
ومشاركة الأسرار والقصص مع الطلبة.
And sometimes afterwards I'll stick around
وأحيانا أبقى بعد الانتهاء
and sign books and take photos with students.
فأوقع الكتب وألتقط صورا مع الطلبة.
And this next postcard was made
وهذه البطاقة التالية تم تشكيلها
out of one of those photos.
من واحدة من تلك الصور.
And I should also mention that, just like today,
يجدر بي كذلك أن أذكر أنه، تماما مثل اليوم،
at that PostSecret event,
في حدث PostSecret ،
I was using a wireless microphone.
كنت أستخدم لاقطا لاسلكيا.
"Your mic wasn't off during sound check.
"لاقطك لم يكن مطفأ أثناء التحقق من الصوت.
We all heard you pee."
سمعناك جميعا وأنت تتبول."
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
This was really embarrassing when it happened,
كان هذا محرجا للغاية حين حصل،
until I realized it could have been worse.
حتى أدركت أنه كان ليكون أسوأ.
Right. You know what I'm saying.
صحيح. تعرفون ما أقصده.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
"Inside this envelope
"داخل هذا المظروف
is the ripped up remains
بقايا ممزقة
of a suicide note I didn't use.
لرسالة انتحار لم أستخدمها.
I feel like the happiest person on Earth (now.)"
أحس وكأنني أسعد شخص على الأرض (الآن)"
"One of these men is the father of my son.
"أحد هؤلاء الرجال والد ابني.
He pays me a lot to keep it a secret."
يدفع لي الكثير للإبقاء على الأمر سرا."
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
"That Saturday when you wondered where I was,
"يوم السبت حين تساءلت أين كنت،
well, I was getting your ring.
حسنا، كنت أحضر لك خاتمك.
It's in my pocket right now."
إنه في جيبي الآن."
I had this postcard posted on the PostSecret blog
قمت بوضع هذه البطاقة على مدونة PostSecret
two years ago on Valentine's Day.
قبل سنتين في يوم الحب.
It was the very bottom, the last secret in the long column.
كانت في أقصى الأسفل، آخر سر في عمود طويل.
And it hadn't been up for more than a couple hours
ولم يتم رفعها سوى قبل سويعات
before I received this exuberant email
قبل أن أستقبل هذا البريد الإلكتروني الهائل
from the guy who mailed me this postcard.
من الشخص الذي أرسل هذه البطاقة البريدية.
And he said, "Frank, I've got to share with you
وقد قال، "فرانك، يجب أن أشاركك هذا
this story that just played out in my life."
هذه القصة التي حصلت للتو في حياتي."
He said, "My knees are still shaking."
قال، "ركبتاي لا تزالان ترتعدان."
He said, "For three years, my girlfriend and I,
قال، "لمدة ثلاث سنوات، أنا وصديقتي الحميمة،
we've made it this Sunday morning ritual
كنا نقوم كل يوم أحد
to visit the PostSecret blog together
بزيارة مدونة PostSecret معا
and read the secrets out loud.
وقراءة الأسرار بصوت عال.
I read some to her, she reads some to me."
أقرأ بعضها لها، وتقرأ بعضها لي."
He says, "It's really brought us closer together
قال، "لقد جعلتنا أقرب إلى بعضنا البعض بكثير
through the years.
على مدى الأعوام.
And so when I discovered
وبالتالي حين اكتشفت
that you had posted
أنك قد نشرت
my surprise proposal to my girlfriend at the very bottom,
عرض زواجي لصديقتي الحميمة في أقصى الأسفل،
I was beside myself.
كنت متحمسا للغاية.
And I tried to act calm, not to give anything away.
وحاولت أن أبقى هادئا، حتى لا أفضح نفسي.
And just like every Sunday,
وتماما ككل يوم أحد،
we started reading the secrets out loud to each other."
بدأنا نقرأ الأسرار جهرا لبعضنا البعض."
He said, "But this time it seemed like it was taking her forever
قال، "لكن هذه المرة بدا وكأنه تستغرق ما لا نهاية
to get through each one."
لتصل إلى الأخرى."
But she finally did.
لكنها فعلت أخيرا.
She got to that bottom secret, his proposal to her.
وصلت إلى ذلك السر في الأسفل، عرض زواجه لها.
And he said, "She read it once and then she read it again."
وقال، "قرأته مرة وقرأته مجددا."
And she turned to him and said,
والتفت إليه وقالت،
"Is that our cat?"
"هل تلك هي قطتنا؟"
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
And when she saw him,
وحين رأته،
he was down on one knee, he had the ring out.
كان منحنيا على ركبته، مخرجا الخاتم.
He popped the question, she said yes. It was a very happy ending.
طرح السؤال، فقالت نعم. كانت نهاية في غاية السعادة.
So I emailed him back
وبالتالي راسلته مجددا
and I said, "Please share with me an image, something,
وقلت، "من فضلك شاركني صورة، شيئا،
that I can share with the whole PostSecret community
يمكن أن أشاركه مع مجتمع PostSecret بأكمله
and let everyone know your fairy tale ending."
وأجعل الجميع يعرف نهاية قصتك الخيالية."
And he emailed me this picture.
وقد أرسل لي هذه الصورة.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
"I found your camera at Lollapalooza this summer.
"وجدت آلة تصويرك في لولابالوزا هذا الصيف.
I finally got the pictures developed
وقد قمت أخيرا بتحميض الصور
and I'd love to give them to you."
وأود أن أعطيك إياها."
This picture never got returned back
هذه الصورة لم يتم إرجاعها أبدا
to the people who lost it,
لمن فقدها،
but this secret has impacted many lives,
لكن هذا السر قد أثر على أرواح كثيرة،
starting with a student up in Canada
بدء بطالب من كندا
named Matty.
يدعى ماتي.
Matty was inspired by that secret
ماتي ألهمه هذا السر
to start his own website,
ليبدأ موقعه الخاص،
a website called IFoundYourCamera.
موقع يسمى IFoundYourCamera
Matty invites people
يدعو ماتي الناس
to mail him digital cameras that they've found,
لإرسال آلات التصوير الرقمية التي وجدوها إليه،
memory sticks that have been lost
شرائح الذاكرة التي فقدت
with orphan photos.
بصور يتيمة.
And Matty takes the pictures off these cameras
ويأخذ ماتي الصور من آلات التصوير تلك
and posts them on his website every week.
وينشرها على موقعه كل أسبوع.
And people come to visit
ويأتي الناس للزيارة
to see if they can identify a picture they've lost
لرؤية ما إذا استطاعوا التعرف على صورة فقدوها
or help somebody else get the photos back to them
أو مساعدة شخص آخر لاسترجاع صوره
that they might be desperately searching for.
التي قد يكون يبحثون عنها بيأس.
This one's my favorite.
هذه هنا هي المفضلة لدي.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
Matty has found this ingenious way
ماتي قد وجد هذه الطريقة العبقرية
to leverage the kindness of strangers.
للاستفادة من عطف الغرباء.
And it might seem like a simple idea, and it is,
وقد تبدو كفكرة بسيطة، وهي كذلك،
but the impact it can have on people's lives can be huge.
لكن التأثير الذي قد تقوم به على حياة الناس يمكن أن يكون ضخما.
Matty shared with me
شاركني ماتي
an emotional email he received
بريدا إلكترونيا عاطفيا استقبله
from the mother in that picture.
من الأم في تلك الصورة.
"That's me, my husband and son.
"تلك أنا وزوجي وابني.
The other pictures are of my very ill grandmother.
الصور الأخرى هي لجدتي المريضة جدا.
Thank you for making your site.
شكرا لإنشائك لهذا الموقع.
These pictures mean more to me than you know.
هذه الصور تعني لي أكثر مما تعرف.
My son's birth is on this camera.
ولادة طفلي توجد على آلة التصوير هذه.
He turns four tomorrow."
سيكون عمره أربع سنوات غدا."
Every picture that you see there
كل صورة ترونها هناك
and thousands of others
وآلاف أخرى
have been returned back to the person who lost it --
تم إرجاعها للأشخاص الذين فقدوها --
sometimes crossing oceans,
أحيانا عبر المحيطات،
sometimes going through language barriers.
وأحيانا مرورا بالحواجز اللغوية.
This is the last postcard I have to share with you today.
هذه هي آخر بطاقة بريدية سأشارككم إياها اليوم.
"When people I love
"حين يترك من أحب
leave voicemails on my phone
رسالة صوتية على هاتفي
I always save them in case they die tomorrow
أقوم دائما بحفظظها في حالة ما إذا ماتوا غدا
and I have no other way
وليس لدي أي طريقة أخرى
of hearing their voice ever again."
لأسمع صوتهم من جديد."
When I posted this secret,
حين نشرت هذا السر،
dozens of people
الكثير من الناس
sent voicemail messages from their phones,
أرسلوا رسائل صوتية من هواتفهم،
sometimes ones they'd been keeping for years,
أحيانا رسائل كانوا يحتفظون بها لسنوات،
messages from family or friends
رسائل من العائلة أو الأصدقاء
who had died.
الذين ماتوا.
They said that by preserving those voices
قالوا أنهم بحفاظهم على تلك الأسرار
and sharing them,
ومشاركتها،
it helped them keep the spirit of their loved ones alive.
ساعدهم ذلك على إبقاء روح أحبائهم حية.
One young girl
إحدى الفتيات
posted the last message
نشرت آخر رسالة
she ever heard from her grandmother.
قد تلقتها من جدتها.
Secrets can take many forms.
الأسرار قد تتخذ أشكالا عديدة.
They can be shocking or silly
قد تكون صادمة أو سخيفة
or soulful.
أو عاطفية.
They can connect us with our deepest humanity
قد تربطنا بإنسانيتنا العميقة
or with people we'll never meet again.
أو بالأشخاص الذين قد لا نلتقيهم مجددا.
Voicemail recording: First saved voice message.
تسجيل رسالة صوتية: أول رسالة صوتية مسجلة.
Grandma: ♫ It's somebody's birthday today ♫
الجدة: ♫إنه عيد ميلاد أحدهم اليوم♫
♫ Somebody's birthday today ♫
♫عيد ميلاد أحدهم اليوم♫
♫ The candles are lighted ♫
♫الشموع مشتعلة♫
♫ on somebody's cake ♫
♫على كعكة أحدهم♫
♫ And we're all invited ♫
♫ونحن جميعا مدعوون♫
♫ for somebody's sake ♫
♫من أجل أحدهم♫
You're 21 years old today.
عمرك 21 سنة اليوم.
Have a real happy birthday, and I love you.
أتمنى لك عيد ميلاد سعيد، وأنا أحبك.
I'll say bye for now.
سأقول وداعا الآن.
FW: Thank you.
ف.و: شكرا لكم.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
Thank you.
شكرا لكم.
June Cohen: Frank, that was beautiful,
جون كوهين: فرانك، ذاك كان جميلا،
so touching.
مؤثرا للغاية.
Have you ever sent yourself a postcard?
هل بعثت قط ببطاقة بريدية لنفسك؟
Have you ever sent in a secret to PostSecret?
هل بعثت قط بسر إلى PostSecret؟
FW: I have one of my own secrets in every book.
ف.و: لدي سر خاص بي في كل كتاب.
I think in some ways, the reason I started the project,
أظن أنه بطريقة ما، السبب الذي جعلني أبدأ المشروع،
even though I didn't know it at the time,
رغم أنني لم أعرفه آنذاك،
was because I was struggling with my own secrets.
كان لأنه كنت أعاني مع أسراري الخاصة.
And it was through crowd-sourcing,
وقد كان عن طريق التعهيد الجماعي،
it was through the kindness that strangers were showing me,
عن طريق العطف الذي أظهره الغرباء لي،
that I could uncover
أن استطعت أن أكشف
parts of my past that were haunting me.
أجزاء من ماضيي كانت تطاردني.
JC: And has anyone ever discovered
ج. ك: وهل اكتشف أحد قط
which secret was yours in the book?
أي سر هو لك في الكتاب؟
Has anyone in your life been able to tell?
هل استطاع أحد في حياتك أن يعرف؟
FW: Sometimes I share that information, yeah.
ف. و: أحيانا أشارك تلك المعلومات، صحيح.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
(Applause)
(تصفيق)